Artur Vanivskyi - Software Developer

New York, NY | 646-830-9748 | vanivskyi.artur@gmail.com | Linkedin | GitHub | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Full-Stack software engineer proficient in using JavaScript for front-end and back-end programming, React, HTML, CSS, API implementing, Node.JS, Express, PostgreSQL, and frameworks like Bootstrap. Problem solver with experience developing logical and methodical solutions to problems. A keen eye for design, allowing for the development of visually pleasing and user-friendly website designs.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Frontend: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, jQuery.
- Backend: Node.js, Express, RESTful APIs, PostgreSQL.
- Tools: Mocha, Chai, Knex, Git, GitHub, Heroku, Node Package Manager, Visual Studio Code.
- Additional Skills: Languages: Ukrainian (fluent), Russian (fluent), Polish.

EXPERIENCE

Thinkful Remote

Full-Stack Engineering Student

06/2022 - 11/2022

- Learned industry best practices and software development standards with a focus on JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, React Native, Node.js, PostgreSQL, RESTful APIs, algorithms, and data structures.
- Developed and deployed mobile-first applications while learning new languages and frameworks, spending several hours per week collaborating with and learning from senior web developers in a mentor-student relationship.
- Produced professional projects from concept to completion including:
 - Movie Database Application | WeLoveMovies
 - Assembled the back end of a movie website allowing any user to search for their favorite movies.
 - Built an API following RESTful design principles.
 - Used CRUD methods for reviews, and viewing theaters and movies that are showing.
 - Applied router and controller functions to retrieve a user's specific requests.
 - Deployed the backend server to a cloud server.
 - **Technology:** Node.js, Express, and Knex. Version control with Git.
 - > Restaurant Reservation System | Reservation-System
 - Full stack reservation and table management system.
 - Implemented react router and express to build a RESTful API in order to make HTTP requests for all of the reservation data stored on the connected PostgreSQL database.
 - Created CRUD functions and knex queries to handle data going to and coming from the database.
 - Used Git to track changes and versions while keeping sensitive information from being pushed to repositories.
 - Technology: React, Node is, Express, Knex and PostgreSQL.
 - > Study Tool Application | Flashcard
 - Designed an application that allows users to create, edit, and delete decks and cards within them.
 - Created a REST API and middleware functions to allow user(s) to create, read, update and delete.
 - Defined routes and URLs, and used state over multiple components.
 - **Technology:** JavaScript, React, Express, Knex, HTML, and CSS. Progress/Versions tracked with Git.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Masal / Masal Plus Brooklyn, NY

Manager

■ 04/2018 - 08/2022

■ Completed store operational requirements by scheduling and assigning employees, and followed up on results.

- Maintained store staff by recruiting, selecting, orienting, and training employees.
- Achieved financial objectives by preparing an annual budget.
- Formulated pricing policies by reviewing merchandising activities, and determined needed sales promotions.

GasInfoService Ukraine

Project Manager of Geology and Geophysics department

05/2016 - 08/2017

- Developed a database of various businesses which use and convey all varieties of equipment used in the Geology and Geophysics surveys and closed 24 deals for the company.
- Presented various presentations about the company and services at conferences.
- Built the structure for the web page in the Geology and Geophysics section.

EDUCATION

Thinkful Online Certificate, Software Engineering 06/2022 - 11/2022

AGH University of Science and Technology

Cracow, Poland

MS, Applied Geophysics

09/2015 - 02/2017

Ivano-Frankivsk National Technical University of Oil and Gas

MS, Geophysics

1vano-Frankivsk, Ukraine
09/2015 - 02/2017

Ivano-Frankivsk National Technical University of Oil and Gas

B.S, Geology

Ivano-Frankivsk, Ukraine
09/2011 - 06/2015